Guide to the Johnson family papers, 1816-1936.
Johnson family papers, 1816-1936.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Johnson family papers, 1816-1936.
1200
Johnson family.
5 cubic ft.
Deeds, bills, accounts, correspondence, membership papers, cathedral rubbings, maps, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Family and business papers of Benjamin Johnson, including early Tompkins county deeds; bills; gristmill, teamsters', and personal accounts (1816-1878); correspondence and papers relating to the interest of Jesse Johnson and Charles D. Johnson in the Ithaca Calendar Clock Company and in a brick-making venture (1867-1870); membership papers of Charles D. Johnson in the Royal Templars of Temperance (1880); numerous letters written to family and business associates by Benjamin Johnson, a grandson of the first Benjamin, from Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Kansas, and elsewhere in the West (1883-1896), where he was employed by the Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe railroad; some correspondence of his brother, Frederic Treman Johnson (1886-1890); cathedral rubbings made while the latter was in England (1907), and bills, accounts and maps for that trip.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
This collection contains records by and about Benjamin Johnson (1784-1848), his son Charles D. Johnson and grandsons Benjamin Johnson and Frederic Treman Johnson. Benjamin Johnson came to Ithaca, N.Y. around 1818.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Family and business papers of Benjamin Johnson, including early Tompkins county deeds; bills; gristmill, teamsters', and personal accounts (1816-1878); correspondence and papers relating to the interest of Jesse Johnson and Charles D. Johnson in the Ithaca Calendar Clock Company and in a brick-making venture (1867-1870); membership papers of Charles D. Johnson in the Royal Templars of Temperance, a total abstinence society (1880); numerous letters written to family and business associates by Benjamin Johnson, a grandson of the first Benjamin, from Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Kansas, and elsewhere in the West (1883-1896), where he was employed by the Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe railroad; some correspondence of his brother, Frederic Treman Johnson (1886-1890); cathedral rubbings made while the latter was in England (1907), and bills, accounts and maps for that trip. Included are correspondence and other papers of Elijah B. Cornell, A. Ward Gregory, George Hackney, Mary L. Tait, T. W. Welsh.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Johnson family.; Cornell, Elijah B.; Gregory, A. Ward.; Hackney, George.; Johnson, Benjamin, 1784-1848.; Johnson, Benjamin.; Johnson, Charles D.; Johnson, Frederic Treman.; Johnson, Jesse.; Tait, Mary L.; Welsh, T. W.; Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railroad.; Ithaca Calendar Clock Company.; Royal Templars of Temperance--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Subjects:
Brickmaking--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Flour-mills--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Clock and watch industry--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Railroads--Employees.; Teamsters--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Temperance--Societies, etc.; Industries--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Industries--New York (State)--Tompkins County.
Places:
West (U.S.)--Description and travel.; Colorado--Description and travel.; Kansas--Description and travel.; Nevada--Description and travel.; New Mexico--Description and travel.; England--Maps, Tourist.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Economic conditions.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Rubbings.; Tourist maps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PARTIAL CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1882-1884 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Mar. 1885 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Apr.-May 1885 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, June-Aug. 1885 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Sept.-Dec. 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1886 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Mar.-Apr. 1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, May-Oct. 1886 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Nov.-Dec. 1886 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, Jan.-Apr. 1887 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, May 1887-Dec. 1889 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, Apr.-Sept. 1891 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Jan.-May 1892 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, June-Aug. 1892 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, Sept.-Dec. 1892 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Feb.-Nov. 1893 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, May-Dec. 1894 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1895-1896, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1907, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Papers, 1818-1842 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Papers, 1858-1880 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Papers, 1878-1881 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Great Britain travel notes, brochures (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Great Britain travel, maps (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Episcopal Church - articles, pictures (Box 2, Folder 3)